TEJÁL CHANDRAKANT VAIDYA

Address - Sai Raj CHS, Kharghar 410210, Navi Mumbai

Mobile No: 9975493076/7977704773 Email – <u>tejalvaidya8@gmail.com</u> Date of Birth – 08 October 1992.

Objectives

Senior Officer (Network) with 5+ years of work experience in Routing, Switching, Implementation and Troubleshooting of network system as well as understanding of Firewall technologies. Widely capable in configuring and troubleshooting of routing protocols OSPF, BGP, EIGRP and Network protocol used as VLAN, IS-IS, IPv4.

Professional Experience

Reliance Communication Ltd., Koparkhairane, Maharashtra

Senior Officer (Network), Dec 2017-Nov 2021

- Worked in Process Managed Service Operations Center department to maintain network security policies and monitor compliance.
- Evaluate Local Area Network (LAN) or Wide Area Network (WAN) performance data to ensure sufficient availability or speed, to identify network problems, or for disaster recovery purposes.
- Involved L1/L2 Switching Technology Administration including creating and managing VLAN's, Port security, STP, Inter-VLAN routing, LAN security.
- Coordinate with Enterprise-Wide-Networks Teams to validate network alerts.
- Responsible for providing tier 1 and tier 2 support to TAC, Field Engineers, and 300+ Telecom Operators/Corporate Customers.
- Worked with OSP Teams to Identify major Fiber Faults.
- Effectively resolved routing issues within multiple contexts of the Cisco ASA firewall.

Vertex Customer Management (I) Pvt. Ltd., Mahape, Maharashtra

Technical Support Executive, March 2016-July 2017

- Maximized network availability and performance by monitoring troubleshooting, resolving outages and scheduling upgrades.
- Performed initial analysis of 100+ network issues while resolving and escalating as needed to ensure business
 operations productivity.
- Reviewed system logs to determine usage levels, bandwidth, performance, and system security to target inefficiencies and implement appropriate solutions.
- Provided smooth communications by configuring LAN technology, wireless access points and controllers.

Hexaware Technologies Ltd., Mahape, Maharashtra

Executive, Nov 2014-March 2016

- Provided Process claims as per healthcare guidelines.
- Timely and accurate Adjudication of all types of claims from assigned workflow queues.
- Effective communication with supervisors verbally or in writing regarding claims issues including claim adjudication, overpayments, underpayments, billing problems and any other irregulations.
- Process the claims (claims payment) according to the group/plan validation and meet the clients SLA in terms of TAT and Quality.

Educational Qualification

- 1. Completed Master's in Computer Science, **Computer Application (MCA)** from University of Mumbai, in January 2021.
- Completed Bachelor of Science, Computer Science (BCS) from Karmaveer Bhaurao Patil College, Vashi (Maharashtra) in April 2015.
- 3. Completed HSC from Motilal Jhunjhunwala College, Vashi (Maharashtra) in February 2010.
- 4. Completed SSC from Adarsh Vidya Mandir, Badlapur (Maharashtra) in March 2008.

Technical Skills

Network Technology - Cisco Router, Cisco Switch, Network management, Firewalls, Firewalls principles. Tools – Clarity, Putty, MS-Office, Citrix, Ticketing tools.

Key Strengths

The ability to creating a positive work with others Strong work ethic Self-motivated

Interests

Drawing, Sketching and Painting Reading Articles, Magazines etc. Solving Puzzles Games

Tejal Chandrakant Vaidya